[
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "To create web pages",
      "To make web pages interactive and dynamic and Alive",
      "To make webpages are stylish.",
      "To create server applications"
    ],
    "answer": "To make web pages interactive and dynamic and Alive"
  },
  {
    "question": "JavaScript converts a ______ website into a ______ website.",
    "options": [
      "Dynamic → Static",
      "Static → Dynamic",
      "Secure → Insecure",
      "Server → Client"
    ],
    "answer": "Static → Dynamic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a real-time use case of JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "Form validations",
      "Popup alerts",
      "Event handling",
      "Database table creation",
      "Get Realtime Updates"
    ],
    "answer": "Database table creation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Form data can be submitted to:",
    "options": [
      "Only JavaScript",
      "Only Server",
      "JavaScript and Server",
      "Browser only"
    ],
    "answer": "JavaScript and Server"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the full form of ECMA?",
    "options": [
      "European Computer Manufacturers Association",
      "Electronic Computer Management Association",
      "European Council Modern Applications",
      "Enterprise Computing Manufacturers Alliance"
    ],
    "answer": "European Computer Manufacturers Association"
  },
  {
    "question": "JavaScript validations come under:",
    "options": [
      "Server-side validation",
      "Client-side validation",
      "Database validation",
      "Network validation"
    ],
    "answer": "Client-side validation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organization originally developed JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "W3C",
      "ECMA",
      "Netscape Communications",
      "Microsoft"
    ],
    "answer": "Netscape Communications"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where should internal JavaScript be written?",
    "options": [
      "Inside <body> without tag",
      "Under the head section using script tag in HTML file",
      "Under the section using head tag in HTML file",
      "Inside <style> tag."
    ],
    "answer": "Under the head section using script tag in HTML file"
  },
  {
    "question": "External JavaScript files are saved with which extension?",
    "options": [
      ".html",
      ".css",
      ".js",
      ".java"
    ],
    "answer": ".js"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of <script src=\"myscript.js\"></script>?",
    "options": [
      "Creates internal script",
      "Links external JavaScript file",
      "Compiles JavaScript",
      "Executes CSS"
    ],
    "answer": "Links external JavaScript file"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a JavaScript data type?",
    "options": [
      "Number",
      "String",
      "Character",
      "Boolean",
      "Bigint"
    ],
    "answer": "Character"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should a you focus on to get a job in Full Stack development easily?",
    "options": [
      "Frontend technologies like HTML, CSS, JS, ReactJS(React as main library)",
      "Backend technologies like Java, .NET, Python(REST APIs as main focus)",
      "Database technologies like Oracle, MySQL",
      "Code should be on GitHub and at least one live project",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is TRUE about JavaScript variables?",
    "options": [
      "Data type must be declared",
      "Data type is decided at runtime",
      "Only numbers are allowed",
      "Variables cannot change type"
    ],
    "answer": "Data type is decided at runtime"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is TRUE about JavaScript variables? (Type II)",
    "options": [
      "Data type must be declared statically typed.",
      "Data type is decided at runtime dynamically types.",
      "Depends on requirement decide the data type declaration.",
      "Variables cannot change type of the data."
    ],
    "answer": "Data type is decided at runtime dynamically types."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the typeof operator?",
    "options": [
      "To convert data",
      "To check value exists",
      "To check data type",
      "To compare values"
    ],
    "answer": "To check data type"
  },
  {
    "question": "Analyze the code: let empId = 1001; console.log(typeof empId); What will be the output?",
    "options": [
      "string",
      "number",
      "bigint",
      "int"
    ],
    "answer": "number"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a data type in programming?",
    "options": [
      "To store multiple values in one variable",
      "To define the type of data a variable can hold.",
      "To execute conditional statements",
      "To display output on the screen"
    ],
    "answer": "To define the type of data a variable can hold."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is validation in web development?",
    "options": [
      "Styling the web page using CSS",
      "Checking and verifying user input before processing or storing it",
      "Sending data to the server",
      "Displaying output on the web page"
    ],
    "answer": "Checking and verifying user input before processing or storing it"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invented JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "Tim Berners-Lee",
      "Brendan Eich",
      "Dennis Ritchie",
      "James Gosling"
    ],
    "answer": "Brendan Eich"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the latest official standard version of JavaScript (ECMAScript) as of 2026?",
    "options": [
      "ES2024",
      "ES2025",
      "ES2026",
      "ES6"
    ],
    "answer": "ES2026"
  }
]